SAMIULLAH KHWAJA

sami.skhwaja@gmail.com • 209 281 6339 • Concord, CA 94521

Permanent Work Authorization • No Visa Sponsorship Required • Open to Relocation

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

IT professional with 8+ years of experience in IT Support and System Administration Technical Operation support, Software Development with a knowledge of side in Windows Server, Jamf, Air-Watch, JIRA, Confluence, Service Now, Okta, MacOS, AWS, Linux, Git, Jenkins.

KEY SKILLS

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- CompTIA A+ Certified
- Implement, enforce and monitor standardized operating procedures and policies relating to IT Support and in alignment with ITIL standards.
- IT Support Specialist III: Leading a team of 4, white gloves technical support to the executives and C-Level personnel in a corporate environment.
 - o MacOS, Cellular, iOS, Office 365, Air-watch, Windows 10, Okta Admin
- Multi-Lingual: English, Persian and Hindi

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Support Specialist III

XOLV Walnut Creek, CA

May 2018 - Ongoing

- Adhere to standardized operating procedures and policies relating to IT Support
- Support IT Support objectives / projects such as Win7 Win10 Migration, MS O365 Migration for over 1000+ Employees in Corporate office and 7 Remote offices.
- AV support for Town Hall meetings within and outside the organization using Zoom Webinar for the Video broadcasting.
- Manage a team of 4 personal and provide white gloves technical support to the executives and C-Level Managers in a corporate environment.
- Suggest improvements to processes and procedures to improve efficiency
- Support VoIP desk phone system across the organization for over 700+ Polycom phones.
- Remote, chat, over the phone and walk-in assistance using Jira and Service Now ITSM ticketing system
- Creating SOPs for how to resolve any known issues in Confluence.
- Provide training to new started technicians in the department.
- Review and QA any C-Level equipment deployment.
- Create user, grant access in AD Manager.
- Equipment deployment in for on-boarding employees.

Computer Desktop Technician

UPS (United Postal Service) UPS-Hub Lathrop, CA

June 2017 - May 2018

- Deployed and installation of Windows Operation system over the Ethernet in a virtualized environment.
- Performed Technology support in Active Directory for users and Computers such as Addition, removal and modify.
- Performed Technology Support for Customers and support UPS Core Technology solutions using online
 Ticketing System assigned by high level management and corporate.

- Resolved 8 10 tickets on daily basis to UPS Small Package, Freight and SCS locations to supporting UPS Technology Infrastructure.
- Performed Equipment exchange and recording inventory controls, software installations and program updates, troubleshooting and problem resolution on computer and Telecommunication systems.
- Trained users on supported software and hardware with understanding of technology from a user perspective as well as technical perspective.
- Assist users to resolve computer related problems such as inoperative hardware or software.

Help Desk/Telephone Technician Dec 2015 – Jan 2017

Department of Sate U.S. Embassy Kabul, Afghanistan

- Worked in a HIPPA/HITECH complaint environment for 13 Months
- Performed System administration such as Active Directory, DHCP, Laptop Desktop break fix and Hardware & software installation.
- Remotely support to distanced users and clients, windows 7, 8 and 10 troubleshooting, MS Office and Lookup configuration to mobile devices.
- Resolved an average of 5 tickets on daily bases using a US Embassy ticketing system and Microsoft SharePoint.
- Carried out transition of old TDM Telephone system to new VoIP Telephone system
- Performed Infrastructure Networking of US Embassy, Kabul for the old and new buildings and connected them through Fiber Optic SM/MM backbone
- Managed phone Master 6 application maintenance and PBX telephone system programming
- Managed and supervised 4 people for the projects like: Ladder Rack Installation, 42RU Rack Mounting,
 Installation of Cisco Switches, LANs with Fiber Optic and CAT-6 patch panels and have been successfully completed on time and less budget.

IT Officer April 2010 – June 2014 USAID/Deloitte LLP, Kabul, Afghanistan

International consulting firm with 220,000 employees worldwide

EDUCATION

Bachelors, Computer Science 2014

Kardan University, Kabul, Afghanistan

Ranked 1st and is the first private institution tertiary education in Afghanistan in the field of Information Technology/Computer Sciences and Business Administration.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT/ASSOCIATIONS

AWS Certified – Cloud practitioner 2018
Certified CompTIA A+ Certification 2016

Code: Q0WNENGN1HEQC2SY

Verify at: http://verify.CompTIA.org